That dream again.
Znowu ten sen.
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
There's certainly a wide variety of types, isn't there?
Są różne rodzaje, prawda?
Tamiya Ryoko, the teacher, was already a surprise,
Tamiya Ryoko była zaskoczeniem,
but now we have a politician.
a teraz mamy polityka.
He can't possibly get elected without a solid grasp of human psychology.
Nie wygra bez świetnej znajomości ludzkiej psychiki.
He won't get elected.
Nie wybiorą go.
He'll show his true colors soon enough.
Niedługo pokaże swoją prawdziwą twarz.
Wait. Given the town he's in,
Chwila. Jest w tym mieście,
Tamiya Ryoko may be involved, too.
więc Tamiya Ryoko też może być w to zamieszana.
-Then is there a connection between… -You're way too worked up over this.
- Z Shimadą też go coś łączy? - Za dużo o tym myślisz.
-That would mean-- -What's his goal?
- Czy to znaczy… - Jaki ma cel?
Yes, exactly!
Właśnie!
The first possibility is, by assuming a human identity
Możliwe, że gdy przyjął ludzką postać
and studying mankind,
i bliżej poznał wasz gatunek,
he developed a real interest in politics.
zainteresowała go polityka.
If that is the case, he may actually become a decent mayor.
Czyli może być porządnym burmistrzem.
No way.
Nie wierzę w to.
The second possibility is,
Druga opcja jest taka,
he wants to secure a safe haven and food source for parasites.
że chce zapewnić bezpieczeństwo i pożywienie innym pasożytom.
You have a point.
To ma sens.
Even if they hide the body after they feed,
Ale gdy kogoś zjedzą,
that still results in missing persons.
ta osoba będzie poszukiwana.
If they happen to kill a celebrity, there'd be an uproar.
Jeśli zabiją jakąś gwiazdę, wybuchnie afera.
Attaining a position with access to information is more advantageous
Będąc na wysokim stanowisku, może zapobiegać takim sytuacjom
So that's his goal.
Więc o to mu chodzi.
If they organize, they'll become even more dangerous.
W grupie będą jeszcze bardziej niebezpieczne.
That'd put her at risk, too.
Ona też będzie zagrożona.
But it is at the municipal level
- Problemy środowiskowe… - Chodźmy stąd.
-Oh. -…can be addressed in a practical sense.
…można rozwiązywać na szczeblu gminnym…
That wasn't where we agreed to meet up.
Nie tam mieliśmy się spotkać.
Why were you there?
Co tam robiłaś?
I had a strong feeling that you were there.
Czułam, że tam jesteś.
I told you not to approach even if you had that sensation.
Miałaś nie podchodzić w takich sytuacjach.
But it wasn't just you.
Nie czułam tylko ciebie.
I could sense it from the people behind you, too.
Czułam też ludzi, którzy za tobą stali.
I'd say there were four or five of them.
Było ich czterech albo pięciu.
Migi said there were eight,
Migi mówił, że było ich ośmiu,
so her ability to sense parasites isn't as strong as theirs.
więc ona wyczuwa je słabiej niż one.
But this places her in too much danger.
Ale przez to grozi jej niebezpieczeństwo.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
What are you thinking about?
O czym myślisz?
Nothing!
O niczym!
It's none of your business what I'm thinking about.
Nie twoja sprawa, o czym myślę.
I was just curious.
Byłem ciekaw.
HIROKAWA TAKESHI CANDIDATE FOR MAYORAL ELECTION
HIROKAWA TAKESHI KANDYDAT NA BURMISTRZA
From where I stand,
Chciałbym, żebyś się w to nie angażował.
Even if we were to fight them, we would lose.
Nie mamy z nimi szans.
I didn't come here to fight.
Nie przyszedłem tu walczyć.
I just want to know how many of them have gathered here.
Chcę tylko wiedzieć, ilu ich tutaj jest.
It's impossible to count their numbers.
Nie można ich dokładnie policzyć.
An estimate is fine.
Wystarczy przybliżona ilość.
Aren't you curious to know how others of your kind have evolved?
Nie jesteś ciekaw, jak ewoluowali?
Well, sure.
Jestem.
Well?
No i?
It's only when you go looking for them that you can't find them.
Gdy ich szukasz, nie możesz ich znaleźć.
Oh, Izumi!
Izumi!
Hi.
Cześć.
What's up?
Co słychać?
I want to ask you something.
Chcę cię o coś zapytać.
About your "superpower".
Ta twoja „supermoc”.
Have you ever felt that sensation from anyone other than me?
Wyczuwasz tak nie tylko mnie?
Huh?
Co?
Oh, yeah.
Tak.
But only sometimes.
Czasami.
When I find them, they sometimes turn out to be a random old dude.
Ale okazują się jakimiś staruchami.
Sorry to sound like a broken record,
Ciągle to powtarzam,
but I want you to keep your distance even if you feel that "signal".
ale nie zbliżaj się do tych, których tak wyczuwasz.
But why?
Dlaczego?
Is it because it's coming from those "parasites"
Bo są tymi pasożytami, o których mówią w Internecie?
Are you a parasite, too?
Też jesteś pasożytem?
-I… I didn't… -Kana.
- Ja nie… - Kana.
Mitsuo!
Mitsuo!
I need to talk to Kana.
Muszę porozmawiać z Kaną.
Okay. Later, then.
Dobrze. To cześć.
Let's continue this later.
Dokończymy to. Chcę z tobą poważnie porozmawiać.
What?
Co?
I'll email you.
Napiszę do ciebie.
You don't need to email.
Nie musisz pisać. Wyczuję cię, gdy będziesz blisko.
"Feel you"?
„Wyczujesz”?
But you said I'm not the only one who can make you feel that.
Mówiłaś, że nie tylko ja tak na ciebie działam.
"Who can make you feel that"?
Nie tylko on?
Kana, you--
Kana, ty…
You idiot!
Idioto!
You've got it completely wrong!
Źle to zrozumiałeś!
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
What is this "serious conversation" you mentioned earlier?
O jakiej poważnej rozmowie mówiłeś?
Was seeing that female your real objective today?
Chciałeś się spotkać z tą dziewczyną?
So what if it was?
A jeśli tak?
Over time, my kind has evolved.
Mój gatunek ewoluował.
But we will never develop what humans call "sympathy".
Ale nigdy nie będziemy czuć tego, co ludzie nazywają współczuciem.
I know that.
Wiem.
Then I ask that you do not put me at risk.
Więc proszę cię, żebyś mnie nie narażał.
If you were to tell her too much…
Jeśli powiesz jej za dużo…
I know.
Wiem.
Do you really?
Naprawdę wiesz?
I'm assuming you wouldn't want to observe your own
Zakładam, że nie chcesz patrzeć,
right hand slicing someone up.
jak twoja prawa ręka kogoś kroi.
Is that a threat?
Grozisz mi?
Yes.
Tak.
You really have no sympathy!
Naprawdę nie masz współczucia!
That's what I just said.
Przecież ci o tym powiedziałem.
I wonder what his "serious conversation" is about.
O czym chce poważnie porozmawiać?
There it is again.
Znowu.
It's close.
Jest blisko.
I don't think it's him, but it could be.
Wątpię, że to on, ale to możliwe.
It's over there.
Jest tam.
Just a little farther, from around that corner.
Trochę dalej, za rogiem.
It wasn't him.
To nie on.
Izumi.
Izumi.
Why here?
Dlaczego tutaj?
Your email said a place without many people around would be best.
Napisałeś o odludnym miejscu.
Okay, he's asleep.
Dobra, śpi.
I told her everything I knew about parasites.
Powiedziałem jej, co wiem o pasożytach.
The one I have just happened to mess up
Ten, który we mnie żyje,
while trying to take over my head and got my right hand instead.
nie przejął mojego mózgu i zamieszkał w mojej ręce.
So he will never attack anyone.
Nigdy nikogo nie zaatakuje.
Now, everything makes sense, right?
Teraz rozumiesz?
I was hoping for something more interesting.
Liczyłam na coś ciekawszego.
I got my hopes up for nothing.
Narobiłam sobie nadziei.
I know it's not easy to believe,
Wiem, że trudno w to uwierzyć,
but everything I just told you is the truth.
ale to, co mówiłem, to prawda.
Show me how your right hand can change shape.
Pokaż, jak twoja prawa ręka się przemienia.
Like I said, he's sleeping right now.
Mówiłem, że teraz śpi.
Just come out and say it.
Po prostu to powiedz.
You just don't want to see me anymore
Nie chcesz się ze mną widywać,
because you don't want that girl, Satomi or whatever, to get the wrong idea.
żeby ta Satomi sobie czegoś nie pomyślała.
That's not it.
Nie o to chodzi.
I wouldn't tell you such an elaborate lie just for something like that.
Nie wymyśliłbym kłamstwa przez taką pierdołę.
"Something like that"?
„Taką pierdołę”?
If you don't like me, just tell me already.
Jeśli mnie nie lubisz, to mi powiedz.
That's not what this is about.
Nie o to tu chodzi.
I have the ability to tell you apart from the rest, you know.
Potrafię odróżniać cię od innych.
Huh? Just me?
Co? Tylko mnie?
Yes.
Tak.
I can tell you apart, specifically, from the rest of those monsters.
Potrafię odróżnić cię od tych potworów.
Really?
Naprawdę?
So I won't approach anyone but you.
Nie będę do nich podchodzić.
-That solves the problem, doesn't it? -Well, I guess…
- Więc po problemie, tak? - Chyba tak.
I'm the only one in the whole world who can do that.
Na całym świecie tylko ja potrafię to robić.
Don't you think that's amazing?
To niesamowite, prawda?
I'm sure it's amazing.
Tak, to niesamowite.
Hey, since I told you my secret,
Powiedziałeś mi o swoim sekrecie.
I want you to show me your secret someday, too.
Chciałabym, żebyś mi go kiedyś pokazał.
What secret?
O jakim sekrecie?
Otherwise, I don't think I can ever really believe your story.
Inaczej nie uwierzę w twoją opowieść.
-All right. -It's a promise, then.
- Dobrze. - Obiecaj.
Sure, I promise.
Obiecuję.
NEWCOMER HIROKAWA ELECTED TO HIGASHI FUKUYAMA MAYORAL OFFICE
HIROKAWA WYGRYWA
He got elected, huh.
Wybrali go.
Parasites have now secured a safe haven and a food source.
Pasożyty zapewniły sobie bezpieczeństwo i źródło pożywienia.
They're as intelligent as humans
Są inteligentne jak ludzie.
and they'd do anything to protect themselves.
Zrobią wszystko, żeby się chronić.
She said she can tell me apart from the rest,
Mówiła, że odróżnia mnie od innych.
but does she really have that kind of power?
Naprawdę ma taką moc?
Impression?
Naprawdę?
Yeah, it's supposed to be a really good movie.
To podobno dobry film.
Both Yuko and Akiho bawled their eyes out.
Yuko i Akiho bardzo na nim płakały.
I'd really like to see it, too.
Też chciałabym go obejrzeć.
All right.
Dobrze.
Tomorrow at ten, then?
To jutro o 10?
Sure.
Jasne.
Why can't you sense me?
Dlaczego mnie nie wyczuwasz?
We're linked by fate.
Połączyło nas przeznaczenie.
I'm the only one who can sense you.
Tylko ja wyczuwam ciebie.
Does she have a power like that?
Ona też ma taką moc?
Come on. Look.
Odwróć się.
Look at me.
Spójrz na mnie.
Don't spook me like that.
Nie strasz mnie tak.
What are you doing?
Co robisz?
What does it matter?
A czy to ważne?
This isn't like you.
To do ciebie niepodobne.
You're like a stalker.
Jesteś jak stalker.
Aren't you the one acting like a stalker, following me around?
To ty nim jesteś, bo wszędzie za mną chodzisz.
He's taken already.
On jest zajęty.
He's not right for you.
Nie jest dla ciebie odpowiedni.
And you are?
A ty jesteś?
Give me a break!
Daj mi spokój!
Quit following me around like a lost puppy.
Łazisz za mną jak jakieś cielę.
I don't ever want to see you again!
Nie chcę cię więcej widzieć!
That was harsh.
To było okrutne.
I didn't know you hated me that much.
Nie wiedziałem, że aż tak mnie nie lubisz.
Sorry, I went too far.
Przepraszam, przesadziłam.
But I can't help how I feel.
Ale to właśnie czuję.
I don't know what to do.
Nie wiem, co robić.
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
I've decided to tell you.
Powiem ci coś.
Huh?
Co?
but I wouldn't want you to do anything rash while I'm asleep, either.
ale nie chcę też, żebyś robił nieprzemyślane rzeczy, gdy śpię.
That female, Kana, her power has grown stronger.
Moc tej dziewczyny, Kany, stała się silniejsza.
Or rather, she's begun to emit a signal.
Zaczęła wysyłać sygnał.
A signal?
Sygnał?
It's a signal parasites emit that lets us sense each other's location.
Pasożyty wysyłają go, żeby zdradzić innym swoje położenie.
I felt hers on our way home from school yesterday.
Wyczułem jej, gdy wracaliśmy ze szkoły.
No way!
To niemożliwe!
If she sends out a signal like that, they'll find her,
Jeśli będzie wysyłać sygnał, to ją znajdą
and she'll get herself killed!
i zabiją!
She probably only emits the signal when she's concentrating intensely.
Wysyła ten sygnał, gdy się mocno skupi.
Its range is quite small as well.
I ma on mały zasięg.
Why didn't you tell me right then?
Dlaczego wcześniej nie powiedziałeś?
Never mind.
Nieważne.
Thank you for telling me.
Dziękuję, że powiedziałeś.
Migi, while you were sleeping the other day,
Migi, wczoraj, gdy spałeś,
I told her everything about the parasites and about you.
powiedziałem jej wszystko o pasożytach i o tobie.
But she wouldn't believe me.
Ale mi nie uwierzyła.
I thought you might've.
- Wiedziałem, że to zrobisz. - Nie będzie twoim wrogiem.
So, because of that, I want you to show yourself to her.
Dlatego chcę, żebyś się jej pokazał.
It'll be fine!
Nic się nie stanie!
If she tells anyone else, I can just bluff.
Jeśli komuś o tym powie, to skłamię.
If you just maintain your cover as my right hand,
Będziesz dalej mieszkał w mojej ręce,
she'll just be dismissed as a high school girl talking nonsense.
a ona będzie dziewczyną, która gada bzdury.
Okay?
Dobrze?
You're right.
Masz rację.
We should hurry, then.
Pospieszmy się.
How about tomorrow?
Może jutro?
I have a date with Murano tomorrow.
Jutro mam randkę z Murano.
SHINICHI KA
SHINICHI KA
We got here early.
Jesteśmy za wcześnie.
Migi, I hope you still remember your promise from yesterday.
Migi, pamiętasz, co wczoraj obiecałeś?
I do.
Tak.
But we have a problem.
Ale mamy problem. Zbliża się ktoś z mojego gatunku.
What?
Co?
INCOMING CALL IZUMI SHINICHI
DZWONI IZUMI SHINICHI
Hello?
Halo.
Sorry, I want to change our meeting place.
Spotkajmy się w innym miejscu.
Whatever you do, don't go near the train station.
Nie zbliżaj się do dworca.
I'll call you back.
Zadzwonię później.
It's those two.
To oni.
-Let's go. -Wait.
- Chodźmy. - Czekaj.
It'll raise their suspicions if we move.
Nabiorą podejrzeń.
Pretend you're making a call.
Udawaj, że dzwonisz.
I'll show you my power properly this time, for sure.
Tym razem naprawdę pokażę ci moją moc.
My power to sense you alone.
To, że tylko ciebie wyczuwam.
No one, not even that girl Satomi, has that special power.
Nikt, nawet Satomi, nie ma takiej mocy.
So you should feel me alone, too.
Więc ty też powinieneś mnie wyczuć.
They acted like we were nothing out of the ordinary.
Uznali nas za coś zwyczajnego.
INCOMING CALL IZUMI SHINICHI
DZWONI IZUMI SHINICHI
Why isn't she picking up?
Dlaczego nie odbiera?
There he is!
Jest!
It's no good.
Niedobrze.
I can't tell her breathing apart from all the other people in this city.
Nie potrafię jej wyczuć wśród tych wszystkich ludzi.
Migi, can't you sense this signal of hers?
Migi, wyczuwasz jej sygnał?
That's impossible.
To niemożliwe.
Her signal is weak compared to others of my kind
Jej sygnał jest słabszy niż u reszty i może go teraz nie wysyłać.
I'll see him.
Zobaczę go.
I'll see him soon!
Zaraz go zobaczę!
Izumi!
Izumi!
There!
Tam!
You found her?
Znalazłeś ją?
No, I detect a signal from my own kind.
Nie, wyczułem sygnał mojego gatunku.
That's useless to us right now.
Teraz jest dla nas nieistotny.
Wait. If Kana detects that signal…
Ale jeśli Kana go wyczuje…
She might approach it.
Może do niego podejść.
Which way?
Gdzie on jest?
See, Izumi? I can tell you apart from everyone else!
Izumi? Potrafię odróżnić cię od innych!
A human?
Człowiek?
I'd thought the signal was too weak to be one of ours, but…
Masz zbyt słaby sygnał, żeby być jedną z nas, ale…
It's okay!
Spokojnie!
He'll come save me!
On mnie uratuje!
Izumi!
Izumi!
Migi.
Migi.
-Handle the defense. -The defense?
- Zajmij się obroną. - Obroną?
Impressive.
Imponujące.
It's too late.
Już za późno. Straciła zbyt dużo krwi.
No.
Nie.
Kana.
Kana.
Izu…
Izu…
Izumi.
Izumi.
I knew you'd come here.
Wiedziałam, że przyjdziesz.
I sensed you.
Wyczułam cię.
Hang in there.
Trzymaj się.
I had a dream like this
Śniło mi się to…
before, too.
już wcześniej.
Don't talk.
Nie mów.
A dream so embarrassing,
Ten sen był bardzo nieprzyzwoity
I could never tell anyone.
i nie mogłam nikomu o nim powiedzieć.
Kana.
Kana.
SHINICHI KA
SHINICHI KA
He's the one who found the victim.
To on odnalazł ofiarę.
He looks calm for someone who was friends with her.
Był jej przyjacielem, a jest taki spokojny.
This is confidential information,
To poufna informacja,
but his mother was also killed by a parasite.
ale jego mamę też zabił pasożyt.
What?
Tak?
Not very friendly, is he?
Nie jest przyjazny.
He must be tired after all the questioning we put him through.
Pewnie jest zmęczony przesłuchaniami.
We even pulled out one of his hairs just in case.
Nawet wyrwaliśmy mu włos.
No wonder he was upset.
Nic dziwnego, że jest zły.
We can't afford to be considerate.
Ostrożności nigdy dość.
The victim was killed by a parasite.
Ofiara została zabita przez pasożyta.
But who killed that parasite?
Ale kto zabił pasożyta?
Something tore through the parasite's ribs, gouged out its heart,
Coś rozerwało mu żebra, wyrwało mu serce
then slammed it against the wall with enough force to destroy the wall itself.
i uderzyło nim o ścianę tak, że się rozwaliła.
No human could do that.
Człowiek by tego nie zrobił.
There must've been at least one more parasite.
Musiało być tam więcej pasożytów.
So, two or more parasites had a falling out?
Pasożyty się ze sobą pokłóciły?
We have to entertain that possibility.
Musimy wziąć pod uwagę taką możliwość.
If only I hadn't promised to see Kana that day
Gdybym nie chciał się spotkać z Kaną
and just went to the movies with Murano, this wouldn't have happened.
i poszedł do kina z Murano, to nic by się nie stało.
You've got it wrong, Shinichi.
Mylisz się, Shinichi.
This was only a matter of time.
To było kwestią czasu.
There is no need for you to feel responsible.
Nie czuj się za to odpowiedzialny.
How can you say something like that?
Jak możesz tak mówić?
Wait!
Stój!
Why…
Dlaczego?
Why couldn't you protect Kana?
Dlaczego nie obroniłeś Kany?
How can you be so calm?
Jak możesz być taki spokojny?
Are you…
Nie potrafisz uronić choćby jednej łzy?
Shinichi!
Shinichi!
You're not human!
Nie jesteś człowiekiem!
That's right!
Masz rację!
Why do you go down so easily?
Tak łatwo cię pokonać?
If we take this any further,
Jeśli posuniemy się za daleko,
we'll just open a hole in this guy's heart, too.
to zrobimy mu w sercu dziurę.
"Not human"?
„Nie jestem człowiekiem”?
He's exactly right.
Ma rację.
Why am I so calm?
Dlaczego jestem spokojny?
Could it be that…
Czy to dlatego…
Could it be that my brain's been taken over without my noticing it?
Czy to dlatego, że przejęto mi mózg, a ja tego nie zauważyłem?
Even though Kana's dead,
Mimo że Kana nie żyje,
I can't cry a single tear.
nie potrafię płakać.
Stop it, Shinichi.
Przestań, Shinichi.
My blood's still red.
Moja krew nadal jest czerwona.
For now.
Jeszcze.
Next time, "Hello Sadness."
Kolejny odcinek: „Witaj, smutku”.